# **BRIAN BURROWS**

+1 (803) 315-2528  $\Leftrightarrow$  Brianjburrow@gmail.com

Brian has six years of experience implementing algorithms and developing APIs in Python and Matlab. He created and implemented machine learning algorithms for autonomous aircraft, performed statistical modeling for natural disasters and nuclear fusion research. He is now developing web apps for orienteering using Python, Flask, Postgresql.

## **SKILLS**

LanguagesPython, Javascript, Matlab, R, HTML, CSS, BashDeveloper ToolsAJAX, Flask, Node.js, Express, SQL-Alchemy, Jasmine, Python unittest, Heroku, DrawIO.Data ToolsSQL, NoSQL, ArcGIS, Tableau, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, PySpark, scikit-learn,<br/>multiprocessing, Seaborn, matplotlib, statsmodels, Tensorflow.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Recent Projects 2020-Present

- Authored a research proposal for wake steering (finalist for NREL's director's fellowship  $\sim 400$  applicants).
- Implemented algorithms for optimal sensor placement, extremum seeking control, and information fusion.
- Developed the full stack for a social media site for orienteering (Python/Flask/JS/jQuery/CSS/HTML/Heroku).
- Created Amazon S3 account and authorized users to upload and serve user images using presigned urls.
- Implemented unit and integration tests using Python's unittest package.
- Created weather forecasting UI using javascript and axios to query OpenWeatherMap's REST API.
- Provided code reviews for data science student at MIT's Policy Hackathon on Environmental Justice.

# Research Scientist I A.I.R. Worldwide, Financial Uncertainty Group, 2019-2020

- Fixed QA issues by creating an ETL pipeline for statistical modeling of insurance claims.
- Fixed QA issues with probability distributions by designing a constrained non-linear optimization problem.
- Created documentation for statistical modeling of earthquakes and simulating wildfires.
- Created data visualizations of natural disasters for various research teams.

### Intern, Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory Center for Applied Scientific Computing, Summer 2017

- Performed exploratory data analysis on 700 terabytes of physics simulations on a Linux supercomputing cluster.
- Efficiently identified errors in physics simulations by using Python's multiprocessing to process big datasets.

#### Graduate Research Assistant, Texas A&M University Computational Design Laboratory, 2014-2019

- Improved accuracy of estimating damage to an aircraft by developing new machine learning algorithms.
- Improved computational cost of estimation by developing approximate Gaussian Process models.
- Enabled scalable design space exploration by refactoring existing simulation code to run on a supercomputer.
- Performed technology review by implementing Transport Maps, Kalman Filters, MCMC, and treed-GP.
- Developed API for each of the above algorithms, published 2 journal articles, and three conference articles.

#### **EDUCATION**

Software Engineering Career Track Certification, Springboard	2022
Applied Data Science Certificate, Massachusetts Institute of Technology	2021
Ph.D. in Mechanical Engineering, Texas A&M University	2019
M.S. in Mechanical Engineering, University of South Carolina	2014
B.S. in Bioengineering, Clemson University	2010

# AWARDS AND HONORS

South Carolina Life Scholarship	2006 - 2010
Tau Beta Pi Engineering Honors Society	2013 - Present
Pi Tau Sigma Mechanical Engineering Honors Society	2014 - Present
PUBLICATIONS	
Probabilistic Methods for Estimating Vehicle Capability in Damaged Composite Aircra	aft 2019
Nonlinear Kalman Filtering with Expensive Forward Models via Measure Change	2019
Analysis of UQ Techniques for Vehicle Capability in Damaged Composite Aircraft	2019
Multitask Aircraft Capability Estimation Using Conjunctive Filters	2017
A Comparison of Naive Bayes Classifiers with Application to Self-Aware Vehicles	2017
Mechanical Percolation in Nanocomposites: Microstructure and Micromechanics	2016
A Data-driven Approach to Multiple Task Capability Estimation	2016